igi-global.com 2019-10-23

# Privacy Policy | IGI Global

_This revised privacy policy will be effective starting on May 25, 2018._

 **Although Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) has always been very open regarding the ways we collect, use, and maintain any personal information shared with us, we want to again pledge that Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) is committed to transparency as it affects users of various Idea Group inc. (dba IGI Global) products, services, and websites/online resources and as such we are providing an expanded privacy policy for your review.**

### What This Policy Covers:

Your privacy is important to us, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use, and share information about you. This policy is intended to help you understand the following:

  * What information we collect about you
  * How we use the information we collect
  * How we store and secure the information we collect
  * How to access and control your information
  * How we transfer the information we collect internationally
  * Other important privacy information

This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our products, services, and websites/online resources, or otherwise interact with Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) (for example, attending Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) events or utilizing various editorial systems), unless a different privacy policy is displayed. This policy also explains your choices about how we use information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you. **If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our products, services, websites/online resources, or interact with any other aspect of our business.**

When we refer to "Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global)", "we," or "us" in this policy, we mean Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global), which controls the information Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) collects when you use the products, services, and websites/online resources. We refer to all of our products, services, and websites/online resources as "Services" in this policy.

## What Information We Collect About You

We collect information about you when you provide it to us, when you use our Services, and when other sources provide it to us, as further described below.

### Information You Provide to Us:

We collect information about you when you input it into the Services or otherwise provide it directly to us.

  *  **Account and profile information:** We collect information about you when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, set preferences, sign-up for or make purchases through the Services. For example, you provide your contact information and, in some cases, billing information when you register for the Services. You also have the option of adding a profile photo, bio, and other details to your profile information to be displayed in our Services. We keep track of your preferences when you select settings within the Services.
  *  **Content you provide through our products:** The Services include the Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) web, desktop and mobile products you use, where we collect and store content that you upload. This content includes any information about you that you may choose to include. Content also includes the files and links you upload to the Services. Examples of content we collect and store include: files uploaded to E-Editorial Discovery or custom institution logo images.
  *  **Content you provide through our websites:** The Services also include our websites owned or operated by us. We collect other content that you submit to these websites, which include social media or social networking websites operated by us. For example, you provide content to us when you provide feedback or when you participate in any interactive features, surveys, contests, promotions, sweepstakes, activities or events.
  *  **Information you provide through our support channels:** The Services also include customer support, where you may choose to submit information regarding a problem you are experiencing with a Service. Whether you designate yourself as a technical contact, open a support ticket, speak to one of our representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support team, you will be asked to provide contact information, a summary of the problem you are experiencing, and any other documentation, screenshots or information that would be helpful in resolving the issue.
  *  **Payment Information:** We collect certain payment and billing information when you register for certain paid Services. For example, we ask you to designate a billing representative, including name and contact information, upon registration. You might also provide payment information, such as payment card details, which we collect via secure payment processing services. We do not store your payment details.

### Information We Collect Automatically When You Use Our Products and Services:

We collect information about you when you use our Services, including browsing our websites and taking certain actions within the Services.

  *  **Your use of the Services:** We keep track of certain information about you when you visit and interact with any of our Services. This information includes the features you use; links you click on; the type, size and filenames of attachments you upload to the Services; frequently used search terms; and how you interact with others on the Services. We also collect information about the teams and people you work with and any communication sent to them through our Services.
  *  **Device and Connection Information:** We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This device information includes your connection type and settings when you install, access, update, or use our Services. We also collect information through your device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device identifiers, and crash data. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better Service experience. How much of this information we collect depends on the type and settings of the device you use to access the Services.
  *  **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) and our third-party partners, such as our advertising and analytics partners, use cookies and other tracking technologies (e.g., web beacons, device identifiers and pixels) to provide functionality and to recognize you across different Services and devices. For more information, please see our Cookies and Tracking Notice, which includes information on how to control or opt out of these cookies and tracking technologies.

## How We Use the Information We Collect

How we use the information we collect depends in part on which Services you use, how you use them, and any preferences you have communicated to us. Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you.

  *  **To provide the Services and personalize your experience:** We use information about you to provide the Services to you, including to process transactions with you, authenticate you when you log in, provide customer support, and operate and maintain the Services. For example, we use the name and picture you provide in your account to identify you to other Service users. Our Services also include tailored features that personalize your experience, enhance your productivity, and improve your ability to collaborate effectively with others by automatically analyzing the activities of your team to provide search results, activity feeds, notifications, connections and recommendations that are most relevant for you and your team. We may use your email domain to infer your affiliation with a particular organization or industry to personalize the content and experience you receive on our websites. Where you use Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) operated services, we may combine information about you and your activities to provide an integrated experience, such as to allow you to find information from one service while searching from another or to present relevant product information as you travel across our websites.
  *  **For research and development:** We are always looking for ways to make our Services smarter, faster, secure, integrated and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people use our Services and feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for integration and improvement of the Services.
  *  **To communicate with you about the Services:** We use your contact information to send transactional communications via email and within the Services, including confirming your purchases, reminding you of subscription expirations, responding to your comments, questions and requests, providing customer support, and sending you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and administrative messages. Depending on your settings, we send you email notifications when you or others interact on the Services. If an opt out is available, you will find that option within the communication itself or in your account settings.
  *  **To market, promote, and drive engagement with the Services:** We use your contact information and information about how you use the Services to send promotional communications that may be of specific interest to you, including by email and by displaying Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) ads on other companies' websites and applications, as well as on platforms like Facebook and Google. These communications are aimed at driving engagement and maximizing what you get out of the Services, including information about new features, survey requests, newsletters, and events we think may be of interest to you. We also communicate with you about new product offers, promotions and contests. You can control whether you receive these communications as described below under "Opt-out of communications."
  *  **Customer support:** We use your information to resolve technical issues you encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, to analyze crash information, and to repair and improve the Services.
  *  **For safety and security:** We use information about you and your Service use to verify accounts and activity, to monitor suspicious or fraudulent activity and to identify violations of Service policies.
  *  **To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights:** Where required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we use information about you in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, and audit functions, and disclosures in connection with the acquisition, merger or sale of a business.
  *  **With your consent:** We use information about you where you have given us consent to do so for a specific purpose not listed above. For example, we may publish testimonials or featured customer stories to promote the Services, with your permission.
  *  **Legal bases for processing (for EEA users):** If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal bases depend on the Services you use and how you use them. This means we collect and use your information only where:
  *     * We need it to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalized features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;
    * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Services and to protect our legal rights and interests;
    * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
    * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place. Where we are using your information because we or a third party (e.g. your employer) have a legitimate interest to do so, you have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Services.

## How We Store and Secure the Information We Collect

We use data hosting service providers in the United States to host the information we collect, and we use technical measures to secure your data. While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

### How Long We Keep Information

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible.

  *  **Account information:** We retain your account information until you delete your account. We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations and to continue to develop and improve our Services. Where we retain information for Service improvement and development, we take steps to eliminate information that directly identifies you, and we only use the information to uncover collective insights about the use of our Services, not to specifically analyze personal characteristics about you.
  *  **Information you share on the Services:** If your account is deactivated or disabled, some of your information and the content you have provided will remain in order to allow your team members or other users to make full use of the Services. For example, we continue to display comments and content you provided to boards or cards.
  *  **Managed accounts:** If the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g., your employer), we retain your information as long as required by the administrator of your account. For more information, see "Managed accounts and administrators" above.
  *  **Marketing information:** If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences unless you specifically ask us to delete such information. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created.

## How to Access and Control Your Information

You have certain choices available to you when it comes to your information. Below is a summary of those choices, how to exercise them and any limitations. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

### Your Choices:

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your information in a structured, electronic format. Below, we describe the tools and processes for making these requests. You can exercise some of the choices by logging into the Services and using settings available within the Services or your account. Where the Services are administered for you by an administrator (see "Notice to End Users" below), you may need to contact your administrator to assist with your requests first. For all other requests, you may contact us as provided in the Contact Us section below to request assistance.

Your request and choices may be limited in certain cases: for example, if fulfilling your request would reveal information about another person, or if you ask to delete information which we or your administrator are permitted by law or have compelling legitimate interests to keep. Where you have asked us to share data with third parties, for example, by enabling a Power-Up, you will need to contact those third-party service providers directly to have your information deleted or otherwise restricted. If you have unresolved concerns, you may have the right to complain to a data protection authority in the country where you live, where you work or where you feel your rights were infringed.

  *  **Access and update your information:** Our Services and related documentation give you the ability to access and update certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can access your profile information from your account and search for content containing information about you using key word searches in the Service. You can update your profile information within your profile settings and modify content that contains information about you using the editing tools associated with that content.
  *  **Deactivate membership to a board, team or enterprise:** You or an administrator can deactivate your access to a board, team or enterprise. If you can deactivate your own access, that setting is available to you in your account settings. Otherwise, please contact your administrator. If you are an administrator and are unable to deactivate an account through your administrator settings, please contact Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) support. Please be aware that deactivating access to a board, team or enterprise does not delete your information from that board, team or enterprise; your information remains visible to other Service users based on your past participation within the Services. For more information on how to delete your information, see below.
  *  **Delete your information:** Our Services and related documentation give you the ability to delete certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can remove content that contains information about you using the key word search and editing tools associated with that content and you can remove certain profile information within your profile settings. Please note, however, that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes, to complete transactions or to comply with our legal obligations.
  *  **Request that we stop using your information:** In some cases, you may ask us to stop accessing, storing, using and otherwise processing your information where you believe we don't have the appropriate rights to do so. For example, if you believe a Services account was created for you without your permission or you are no longer an active user, you can request that we delete your account as provided in this policy. Where you gave us consent to use your information for a limited purpose, you can contact us to withdraw that consent, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place at the time. You can also opt-out of our use of your information for marketing purposes by contacting us, as provided below. When you make such requests, we may need time to investigate and facilitate your request. If there is a delay or dispute as to whether we have the right to continue using your information, we will restrict any further use of your information until the request is honored or the dispute is resolved, provided your administrator does not object (where applicable). If you object to information about you being shared with a third-party app, please disable the app or contact your administrator to do so.
  *  **Opt-out of communications:** You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by using the unsubscribe link within each email, updating your email preferences within your Service account settings menu, or by contacting us as provided below to have your contact information removed from our promotional email list or registration database. Even after you opt out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive transactional messages from us regarding our Services. You can opt out of some notification messages in your account settings. Please note, you will continue to receive generic ads.

You may be able to opt out of receiving personalized advertisements from other companies who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative or who subscribe to the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. For more information about this practice and to understand your options, please visit: [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/), <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/> and [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

  *  **Turn off Cookie Controls:** Relevant browser-based cookie controls are described in our Cookies & Tracking Notice.
  *  **Send "Do Not Track" Signals:** Some browsers have incorporated "Do Not Track" (DNT) features that can send a signal to the websites you visit indicating you do not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, our Services do not currently respond to browser DNT signals. You can use the range of other tools we provide to control data collection and use, including the ability to opt out of receiving marketing from us as described above.
  *  **Data portability:** Data portability is the ability to obtain some of your information in a format you can move from one service provider to another (for instance, when you transfer your mobile phone number to another carrier). Depending on the context, this applies to some of your information, but not to all of your information. Should you request it, we will provide you with an electronic file of your basic account information and the information you create on the spaces under your sole control, like your own boards.

## How We Transfer the Information We Collect Internationally

We collect information globally and primarily store that information in the United States. We transfer, process and store your information outside of your country of residence, to wherever we or our third-party service providers operate for the purpose of providing you the Services. Whenever we transfer your information, we take steps to protect it.

### International Transfers of the Information We Collect

  *  **International transfers to third parties:** Some of the third parties described in this privacy policy, which provide services to us under contract, are based in other countries that may not have equivalent privacy and data protection laws to the country in which you reside. When we share information of customers in the European Economic Area or Switzerland, we make use of the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses, binding corporate rules for transfers to data processors, or other appropriate legal mechanisms to safeguard the transfer. Please see our Privacy Shield Notice below.

### Privacy Shield Notice

Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global) and the U.S.-based corporate affiliates participate in and comply with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks and the Privacy Shield Principles regarding the collection, use, and retention of information about you that is transferred from the European Union or Switzerland (as applicable) to the U.S. We ensure that the Privacy Shield Principles apply to all information about you that is subject to this privacy policy and is received from the European Union, the European Economic Area, and Switzerland.

Under the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, we are responsible for the processing of information about you we receive from the EU and Switzerland and onward transfers to a third party acting as an agent on our behalf. We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for such onward transfers and remain liable in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that we engage to process such information about you on our behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

To learn more about the Privacy Shield Program, and to view our certification, please visit our public Privacy Shield listing.

We encourage you to contact us as provided below should you have a Privacy Shield-related (or general privacy-related) complaint. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please visit our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider, TRUSTe. Through this third-party dispute resolution provider, we have also committed to cooperating and complying with the information and advice provided by an informal panel of data protection authorities in the European Economic Area and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (as applicable) in relation to unresolved complaints (as further described in the Privacy Shield Principles). You may also contact your local data protection authority within the European Economic Area or Switzerland (as applicable) for unresolved complaints.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, including when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted, you may invoke binding arbitration.

We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

## Other Important Privacy Information

### Notice to End Users:

Our products are intended for both personal use and use by organizations. Where the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g. your employer), that organization is the administrator of the Services and is responsible for the end-users and/or Service sites over which it has control. If this is the case, please direct your data privacy questions to your administrator, as your use of the Services is subject to that organization's policies. We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of an administrator's organization, which may be different than this policy.

Even if the Services are not currently administered to you by an organization, if you are a member of a team administered by an organization, or if you use an email address provided by an organization (such as your work email address) to access the Services, then the administrator of that team or the owner of the domain associated with your organizational email address (e.g. your employer) may assert administrative control over your account and use of the Services at a later date. You will be notified if this happens.

Board, team, and enterprise administrators are able to restrict your access to and privileges within the respective board, team or enterprise the administrator controls. In some cases, enterprise administrators can also:

  * Require you to reset your account password;
  * Restrict, suspend or terminate your access to the Services or your account;
  * Control your ability to edit, restrict, modify or delete account information;
  * Change your account information, including profile information or the email address associated with your account;
  * Access information in and about your account;
  * Access or retain information stored as part of your account; and
  * Enable or disable Power-Ups, third-party apps, or other integrations.

If you do not want an administrator to be able to assert control over your account or use of the Services, you should deactivate your membership with the relevant board, team or enterprise or remove any email addresses containing a domain owned or controlled by the administrator entirely from your account. Once an administrator asserts control over your account or use of the Services, you may no longer be able to withdraw membership or change the email address associated with your account without administrator approval.

Please contact your organization or refer to your administrator’s organizational policies for more information.

### Our Policy Toward Children and Adolescents

The Services are not directed to individuals under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children and adolescents under 16. If we become aware that a child or adolescent under 16 has provided us with personal information, we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child or adolescent has provided us with personal information, please contact our support services.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on the Services homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy. Also, a "last updated" note will be visible at the bottom of this page.

 _Note: If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Services and deactivate your account(s), as outlined above._

 _Last Updated by Idea Group Inc. (dba IGI Global): May 25, 2018_
